Last year, I got a chance to watch the new "Star Wars" movie,
في السنة الماضية، حظيت بفرصة مشاهدة فيلم "حرب النجوم" الجديد،
which was fantastic,
وقد كان رائعًا،
but one thing kept bugging me.
ولكن هناك شيء ما ظل يشغل عقلي.
I don't know if you noticed this or not.
لا أدري إذا لاحظت ذلك أو لا.
In this entirely technically advanced world,
في ظل تقدم العالم التام في المجال التقني،
I did not see a single AED anywhere,
لم أرى أي جهازAED في أي مكان،
which was totally shocking --
ذلك كان صادمًا لي تمامًا--
almost as shocking as not knowing what an AED is,
تقريبًا كصدمة عدم معرفة ماهو جهاز الـ AED،
which you guys do know.
الذي تعرفونه ياسادة .
But for those at home,
لكن بالنسبة لأولئك المحليين،
an AED is an automated external defibrillator.
جهاز الـ AED هو عبارة عن جهاز صدمات كهربائية خارجي آلي .
It's the device you use when your heart goes into cardiac arrest
إنه الجهاز الذي تستخدمه عندما تتوقف عضلة القلب عن الاستجابة
to shock it back into a normal rhythm,
لتعرضها للصدمات وتعيدها للضربات الطبيعية،
or, as one of the guys I was teaching a class to referred to it as:
أو، كواحد من الناس كنت أعلم في صف لأشير إليه كـ:
"The shocky-hearty-box thing."
"جهاز الصدمة القلبية"
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
But I really can't blame the Empire,
لكن حقًا لا ألوم الحكومة،
since health and safety regulations
منذ أصبحت الصحة وقوانين السلامة
aren't really their first order of business.
ليست من أولويات أعمالهم.
Though, even if we --
برغم ذلك، حتى لو نحن --
I think worse than not having an AED would be if there was one there,
أعتقد الاسوأ من عدم وجود AED هو وجود واحد في مكان ما،
but just, no one knew where to find it.
لكن ، لا أحد عرف أن يجده.
These devices can drastically increase your chance of survival --
هذه الأجهزة يمكنها أن تزيد من فرص نجاتك بنسبة كبيرة--
almost like a tauntaun on Hoth.
تقريبًا كالتونتون على كوكب الهوث.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
But I'm pretty sure that stormtrooper is going to be toast,
لكنني متأكد بأن جنود العاصفة سيتم تدميرهم،
regardless if we have an AED or not,
بغض النظر إذا كان لدينا أو لا جهاز الـ AED
since what happens is the chest plate is going to be quite hard to get off,
سابقًا كان الذي يحدث هو أن طبقة الصدر ستكون من الصعب جدًا النجاة
and like that tauntaun,
وكذلك مثل التونتون:
the AED has a very short window of time at which it's highly effective.
لجهاز الـ AED يوثر بشكل كبير لمدة قليلة جدًا.
In this case -- basically, we've got to use it within the first 10 minutes.
في هذه الحالة -- بشكل أساسي، علينا استخدامه ضمن العشر دقائق الأولى،
The Jedi, on the other hand, have no problems with their outfits.
لاعبي الجودو، من جهة أخرى، ليس لديهم أية مشكلة بالنسبة للباسهم.
Those robes open straight up,
هذه الثياب مفتوحة على التوالي،
you can place the pads right onto the chest --
يمكنك وضع اللبادات على يمين الصدر--
so upper-right-hand side of the chest,
في الجانب العلوي الأيمن من الصدر،
lower left,
أسفل اليسار
wait for the unit to determine if it's a shockable rhythm
انتظر الوحدة لتحديد إذا كان معدل الصدمة
and get ready to shock.
واستعد للصدمة،
But, the Jedi do have a problem.
لكن، الجودو لديهم مشكلة.
They have a head appendage issue.
لديهم مشكلة ذيل الرأس.
And so I can be totally clear, thinking I'm ready to go,
وهكذا يمكنني أن أكون واضحًا تمامًا، التفكير بأنني مستعد للبدأ،
but I'm accidentally touching a tentacle
لكن عن طريق الخطأ ألمس المجس
and inadvertently shocking myself.
وبدون قصد أقوم بصدم نفسي.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So before you hit that button, make sure you are clear
لذلك قبل الضغط على الزر تأكد من أنك نظيف
and everyone else is clear.
وكل واحد آخر يجب أن يكون نظيف.
Going back to that stormtrooper:
بالعودة إلى جنود العاصفة:
If I did get that chest plate off in time,
إذا قمت بالتخلص من طبقة الصدر في الوقت المحدد،
what would you do if you suddenly found there was a Wookiee under there,
ماذا ستفعل إذا فجأة وجدت أن هناك وحش الوكي،
or possibly two Ewoks?
أو من المحتمل اثنان من الايوكس ؟
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Well, lucky for us,
حسنًا، هذا من حظنا الجيد،
in the kit there's actually a razor,
في الواقع يوجد في العدة موس للحلاقة،
and we can use that to shave the chest on the upper right-hand side
وبإمكاننا استخدام ذلك الموس بحلاقة الجانب العلوي الأيمن من الصدر
and the lower left.
وأسفل اليسار.
Wookiees also have another problem.
الوكيز لديها مشكلة أخرى أيضَا.
They have an accessory issue.
لديهم مشكلة الزينة.
What we want to do is remove these --
الذي نريده هو إزالة هذه--
anything between the two pads we want to remove,
أي شيء بين اللبادتين يجب إزالته،
since it can cause something called "arcing."
سابقًا كان يسبب شيء ما يسمى "الانحناء"
For those who don't know what arcing is,
بالنسبة لأولئك الذين لايعرفون ماهو الانحناء،
do you remember the Emperor,
هل تتذكر الامبراطور،
when he shoots electricity out the ends of his fingers --
عندما يطلق الكهرباء من نهاية أصابعه--
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
that would be kind of like arcing.
ذلك يبدو نوع من الانحناء.
Another thing that --
شيء آخر --
Oh! By the way, he creates that by wearing wool socks under his robes.
عجبًا! على أية حال، تسبب بذلك عن طريق ارتداء جوارب صوفية تحت ثيابه
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
We can also get arcing if we have an extremely wet chest.
يمكننا أيضًا أن ننحني إذا عانينا من ر طوبة في الصدر بشكل حاد.
The electricity travels across the surface instead of through the heart.
الكهرباء تمر عبر السطح بدلًا من مرورها من خلال القلب.
We can correct this with the immortal words of Douglas Adams:
يمكننا تصحيح هذا عن طريق الكلمات الخالدة لـ دوغلاس آدامز:
"Don't panic," which most of us have done today --
"لاداعي للذعر"، حيث معظمنا فعلها اليوم--
and also always having a towel.
ودائمًا بحوزتنا المنشفة.
So, good words to go by.
لذلك، كلمات جيدة للأخذ بها.
The metal bikini -- unfortunately, this is where panic sets in --
البكيني المعدني-- لسوء الحظ، ذلك حيث يبدأ الذعر--
like the modern bra,
مثل حمالة الصدر الحديثة،
we have to make sure we remove,
علينا أن نتأكد من أننا قمنا بإزالتها،
because this can cause severe arcing along with burns.
لأن ذلك قد يسبب انحناء شديد بالإضافة للحروق.
But unfortunately this opens up an issue
لكن لسوء الحظ ذلك يظهر مشكلة
that's almost as controversial as talking about the prequels.
مثيرة للجدل قليلًا كالتحدث حول البرقوليسيين
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
The mere mention of the word "nipples,"
المعنى الخالص لكلمة "حلمات"
and people get into a little bit of a tizzy.
والناس يعتادون على القليل من الرعب
By the way, that is not a nipple, that's a cupcake.
على أية حال، ذلك ليس حلمة، إنها قطعة حلوى.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Chances are, if you do have to use this,
الفرص هي، إذا يتحتم عليك القيام بهذا،
this is going to be on someone you know.
ذلك سيكون على شخص تعرفه.
And remember, everyone has nipples,
وتذكر، كل شخص لديه حلمات،
except for Jabba.
باستثناء الجابا
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
But he does love cupcakes.
لكنه يحب قطع الحلوى
Speaking about Jabba,
التحدث عن الجابا،
if we do have to use an AED on him,
إذا تحتم علينا استخدام الAED عليه،
remember pad placement is the same,
تذكر بأن تجربة اللباد لاتختلف،
even though he doesn't have nipples.
حتى وإن كان لايملك حلمات.
So it's going to be upper right-hand side, lower left.
حيث سيتم وضعه في الجانب العلوي الأيمت، أسفل اليسار.
If we were going through, we're shocking, getting ready to go --
إذا كنا سنبدأ، سنقوم بالصدم، وسنستعد لذلك--
after we've done the shock,
بعد أن نقوم بالصدمة،
one of the things we need to do is remember to do compression.
أحد الأشياء التي نحتاج أن نقوم بها هو تذكر القيام بالضغط.
The preferred method is 30 compressions and two breaths
الطريقة المفضلة هي 30 ضغطة ونفسين اثنين.
in the center of the chest, between the nipples,
في وسط الصدر، بين الحلمات
pressing down at least two inches,
اضغط للأسفل انشين على الأقل،
no more than two and a half,
ليس أكثر من انشين ونصف،
at a rate of at least 100 beats a minute,
بمعدل لايقل عن 100 دقة في الدقيقة،
no more than 120.
ليس أكثر من 120.
Unfortunately, due to the size of Jabba's mouth
لسوء الحظ، بسبب حجم فم الجابا
and also what he puts in said mouth,
وأيضًا ما يضعه في الفم
we may not want to actually do the mouth-to-mouth part.
من المحتمل أننا لانرغب بفعل ذلك عن طريق الفم.
So instead, we can do compression-only CPR.
إذًأ بدلًا من ذلك، نستطيع القيام بضغط فقط ال CPR
The way of remembering the compression-only part
طريقة تذكر ضغط جزء واحد فقط
is we can actually use the Imperial March.
هي أن نستطيع بالفعل استخدام طريقة الامبراطور مارس.
I would sing it for you --
أود أن أغنيها لكم--
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Unfortunately, that would be more something an interrogation droid would do.
لسوء الحظ،
Yoda.
يودا
Small little guy, like a baby.
شاب صغير، كالطفل.
What we do is basically treat him like a baby,
الذي سنفعله بشكل أساسي معالجته كالطفل،
in the sense that we're going to place one pad in the center of the chest
بمعنى أننا سنقوم باستبدال لبادة في منتصف الصدر
and one in the back.
وواحدة في الخلف.
If we place them both in the front,
إذا استبدلناهم كليهما من الأمام،
they can be too close and cause severe arcing,
سيكونونان قريبين جدًا ويسبب انحناء بسيط،
so we want to avoid that.
لذلك نريد أن نتجنب ذلك.
Hopefully, this helped to clarify
أملين، أن ذلك قد ساعد في التوضيح
and put some light on some of the darker issues
وتسليط الضوء على بعض القضايا المعتمة
of using an AED in the Star Wars universe,
باستخدام الـ AED في عالم حرب النجوم،
or any universe in total.
أو أي مكان آخر
I'll leave you with one point.
سأتركك في لحظة معينة،
Remember, if you do find yourself dealing with a Wookiee,
تذكر، إذا وجدت نفسك تتعامل مع الوكيي،
do not shave the entire Wookiee.
لا تقوم بحلق الوكيي بشكل كامل.
This takes way too much time,
ذلك يستغرق وقت كبير،
and it only pisses them off.
وهذا فقط الذي أزعجهم.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Thank you very much.
شكرًا جزيلًا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)